# KEVIN MYLETT

Front-end Web Developer

4 St Lukes Mews, Ushaw Moor, Durham, DH7 7RD T: 0191 373 0274 M: 07545054766 E: kevinmylett@sky.com www.kevinmylett.com www.github.com/kevin-mylett

## Summary

A passionate, self taught web developer with 2 years experience in front-end development. A natural problem solver with a desire to seek solutions, and the ability to multi-task to ensure projects are completed on time. Kevin possesses a meticulous eye for detail and can communicate ideas clearly to technical and non-technical audiences. Enthusiastic and committed with a pro-active approach to personal development.

## Web Development Experience

## 2009 - Present Freelance Web Developer (2years+) & Computer Technician(6 years+) 99 Pixels (Self Employed)

- Responsible for the full development process of new websites, from initial concept and wire framing right through to completion.
- Writing cross browser compatible, easy to read, maintainable code.
- Reviewing code, fixing errors independently and in a timely manner.
- Adhering to modern build processes to bring efficiency to my workflow.
- Writing technical documents, user manuals and providing support to end users.
- Simultaneously managing several projects at any one time.
- Working alongside web designers to transform concepts into fully responsive websites.
- Adding functionality to already existing websites.
- Communicating with fellow developers to help resolve problems.
- Responsible for SEO and adjusting content to make it more search engine friendly.
- Using version control to develop concurrently.

## Skills

HTML 5 | CSS3 | Sass | JavaScript | jQuery | PHP | MySQL | Git | Grunt | Gulp | WordPress | WooCommerce | Bootstrap | SEO | Google Analytics | Server Management | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe Photoshop | XAMPP

## **Previous Work Experience**

2008 - 2009	Helpdesk Advisor - Sony Ericsson (Teleperformance)		
2007 - 2008	Administrative Assistant - Northern Electric Distribution Ltd		
2007	Call Centre Agent - National Savings & Investment		
2007	Voluntary IT Technician - Durham Johnston Comprehensive School		
2004 - 2005	HR Assistant - University of Sunderland		
2003	Customer Advisor - Marks & Spencer PLC		
2000 - 2002	Classroom Assistant - Kumon Maths		

#### Education

2002 - 2006	University of Sunderland	1995 - 2002	Durham Johnston Comprehensive School
	BA(Hons) Business Studies		3 A Levels - Mathematics, Business Studies & Sociology
	Degree Classification: 2:2		1 AS Level - French
			10 GCSE's (A* - C)